Guide to the Peter Reddaway Samizdat collection, 1950-2010 GRC0002
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
- Religious, Circa 1960s to Circa 1990; Series 8
  - Journal, Series 8 Subseries 4
    - Documents of the Christian Committee for the Defense of believers' rights in the USSR - Vol.5:no.2, 1978; Series 8 Subseries 4 (Box 123, Folder 2)
    - Documents of the Christian Committee for the Defense of believers' rights in the USSR - Vol.6, 1978; Series 8 Subseries 4 (Box 123, Folder 3)
    - Documents of the Christian Committee for the Defense of believers' rights in the USSR - Vol.7 -, 1978; Series 8 Subseries 4 (Box 123, Folder 4)
    - Documents of the Christian Committee for the Defense of believers' rights in the USSR - Vol.13 (unedited), 1980; Series 8 Subseries 4 (Box 123, Folder 5)
    - Documents of the Christian Committee for the Defense of believers' rights in the USSR [ Vol. 1 ], 1977; Series 8 Subseries 4 (Box 122, Folder 8)
    - Journal: Istitute of Muslim Minority Affairs, v.2, 1980; Series 8 Subseries 4 (Box 123, Folder 6)
    - Journal: Istitute of Muslim Minority Affairs, v.3:no.2, 1981; Series 8 Subseries 4 (Box 123, Folder 7)
    - Journal: Istitute of Muslim Minority Affairs, v.6:no.2, 1985; Series 8 Subseries 4 (Box 123, Folder 8)
    - Journal: Istitute of Muslim Minority Affairs, v.7:no.2, 1986; Series 8 Subseries 4 (Box 123, Folder 9)
  - Miscellanea, Series 8 Subseries 5
    - Other Religions + Sects [1/2], 1981 September-1988 July 8; Series 8 Subseries 5 (Box 124, Folder 1)
    - Other Religions + Sects [2/2], 1975-1980 March 12; Series 8 Subseries 5 (Box 124, Folder 2)
    - U.S.P. Holdings 480, 1970 December 24-1984 November 11; Series 8 Subseries 5 (Box 149, Folder 2)
    - U.S.P. Holdings 480, 1970 June 30-1978 November 23; Series 8 Subseries 5 (Box 149, Folder 3)
    - U.S.P. Holdings 480, 1971 June 25-1988 November 18; Series 8 Subseries 5 (Box 149, Folder 4)
- Radio Free Europe - Radio Liberty (RFE/RL), 1968-1992; Series 9
  These series Contains documents illustrating the RFE/RL effort in support of human rights activists in the USSR including the rights of young writers.
  Organized into three subseries: Miscellanea, Periodic Lists of Translated Samizdat, Retyped Documents
  - Miscellanea, Series 9 Subseries 1
    - reestr osuzhdennykh ili zaderzhannykh v bor'be za prava cheloveka v sssr s, 1971 February; Series 9 Subseries 1 (Box 124, Folder 3)
    - sovetskie grazhdane zashchishchaiut molodykh literatorov, 1968 January-1968 May; Series 9 Subseries 1 (Box 124, Folder 4)
  - Periodic Lists of Translated Samizdat, Series 9 Subseries 2
    - Archive Organization [1/2], 1973 December 7-1991 January 14; Series 9 Subseries 2 (Box 124, Folder 5)
    - Archive Organization [2/2], 1969 March 20-1973 December 3; Series 9 Subseries 2 (Box 124, Folder 6)
  - Retyped Documents, Series 9 Subseries 3
    - Archive Organiz[ation] [1/3], 1981 December 4-1984 August 10; Series 9 Subseries 3 (Box 124, Folder 7)
    - Archive Organiz[ation] [2/3], 1978 July 17-1981 November 30; Series 9 Subseries 3 (Box 125, Folder 1)
    - Archive Organiz[ation] [3/3], 1977 June 13-1978 July 10; Series 9 Subseries 3 (Box 125, Folder 2)
    - Archive Organiz[ation] [1/2], 1984 August 17-1988 January 29; Series 9 Subseries 3 (Box 125, Folder 3)
    - Archive Organiz[ation] [2/2], 1988 February 1-1992 March 6; Series 9 Subseries 3 (Box 125, Folder 4)
- Social Groups, Circa 1970s - Circa 1980s; Series 10
  These series contain documents illustrating the struggle of disabled citizens of USSR for their rights, as well as the struggle of Soviet independent labor unions and worker's groups. Includes also work by western scholars in support of disabled in USSR.
  Organized into three subseries: Collective, Free Trade Union, Labor Movements
  - Collective, Series 10 Subseries 1
    - Disabled [3/4], 1980 February 1-1981 September 5; Series 10 Subseries 1 (Box 126, Folder 1)
    - Disabled [4/4], 1978 November 10-1981 February 22; Series 10 Subseries 1 (Box 126, Folder 2)
    - Disabled (Invalids) Group [1/2], 1980 February 20-1989 February 10; Series 10 Subseries 1 (Box 126, Folder 3)
    - Disabled (Invalids) Group [2/2], 1978 May 20-1979 December; Series 10 Subseries 1 (Box 126, Folder 4)
    - Feminists, 1979 December-1981 December 13; Series 10 Subseries 1 (Box 126, Folder 5)
    - Samizdat Workers S[vobodnoe] m[ezhprofessional'noe] o[b"edinenie] t[rudiashchisia] - [Aleksei] Nikitin [1/2], 1979 October 11-1985 January 30; Series 10 Subseries 1 (Box 126, Folder 6)
    - Samizdat Workers S[vobodnoe] m[ezhprofessional'noe] o[b"edinenie] t[rudiashchisia] - [Aleksei] Nikitin [2/2], 1977 September 30-1981 September; Series 10 Subseries 1 (Box 126, Folder 7)
    - Disability in the USSR - A Dissident View [-Steven Mark Glick, Masters Thesis for the London School of Economics], 1980 September; Series 10 Subseries 1 (Box 127, Folder 1)
  - Free Trade Union, Series 10 Subseries 2
    - Free Trade Unions [1/2], 1981 April 2-1981 December 14; Series 10 Subseries 1 (Box 127, Folder 2)
    - Free Trade Unions [2/2], 1970 May-1980 December 29; Series 10 Subseries 1 (Box 127, Folder 3)
    - Free Trade Unions [1/2], 1988 June-1998 June 17; Series 10 Subseries 1 (Box 127, Folder 4)
    - Free Trade Unions [2/2], 1981 December-1988 November 25; Series 10 Subseries 1 (Box 127, Folder 5)
  - Labor Movements, Series 10 Subseries 3
    - Workers' Groups, Strikes, 1978 February 1-1988 October 24; Series 10 Subseries 1 (Box 127, Folder 6)
- Western Materials, 1982-1995; Series 11
  These series contain materials concerning the controversial International Physicians for prevention of Nuclear War organization, believed to be an organization lobbying on behalf of the USSR and physicians accused of Psychiatric abuse. Contains reports on Communist activities in Western and Eastern Europe.
  Organized into two subseries: Collective and Miscellanea
  - Collective, Series 11 Subseries 1
    - I[nternational] P[hysicians for the] P[revention of] N[uclear] W[ar], 1985 April 5-1995 February 6; Series 11 Subseries 1 (Box 127, Folder 7)
  - Miscellanea, Series 11 Subseries 2
    - Miscellanea, 1976; Series 11 Subseries 2 (Box 128, Folder 1)
    - Reports on Communist Activities in Eastern and Central Europe [1/2], 1985 May-1989 December; Series 11 Subseries 2 (Box 128, Folder 2)
    - Reports on Communist Activities in Eastern and Central Europe [2/2], 1982 March-1984 October; Series 11 Subseries 2 (Box 128, Folder 3)